The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high-quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Continuing in the theme
教授：继续主题
of sorting in general, but in particular, binary search
排序，但特别是二进制搜索
trees, which are a kind of way of doing
树木，这是一种做事方式
dynamic sorting, if you will, where
动态排序（如果可以）在哪里
the elements are coming and going.
元素来来去去。
And at all times, you want to know the sorted order
而且在任何时候，您都想知道排序顺序
of your elements by storing them in a nice binary search tree.
通过将它们存储在一个漂亮的二进制搜索树中来实现。
Remember, in general, a binary search tree is a tree.
请记住，通常，二叉搜索树是一棵树。
It's binary, and it has the search property.
它是二进制文件，并且具有search属性。
Those three things.
那三件事。
This is a rooted binary tree.
这是一棵有根的二叉树。
It has a root.
它有根。
It's binary, so there's a left child and a right child.
它是二进制的，所以有一个左孩子和一个右孩子。
Some nodes lack a right or left child.
一些节点缺少右孩子或左孩子。
Some nodes lack both.
一些节点缺少两者。
Every node has a key.
每个节点都有一个密钥。
This is the search part.
这是搜索部分。
You store key in every node, and you have this BST property,
您将密钥存储在每个节点中，并且具有此BST属性，
or also called the search property,
或也称为搜索属性，
that every node-- if you have a node the stores key x,
每个节点-如果您有一个节点，则存储密钥x，
everybody in the left subtree stores a key that's less than
左子树中的每个人都存储一个小于
or equal to x, and everyone that's in the right subtree
或等于x，并且每个在正确的子树中的人
stores a key that's greater than or equal to x.
存储大于或等于x的键。
So not just the left and right children,
因此，不仅是左右两个孩子，
but every descendant way down there is smaller than x.
但那里的每个后代都小于x。
Every descendent way down there is greater than x.
那里的每个后代都大于x。
So when you have a binary search tree like this,
因此，当您拥有像这样的二叉搜索树时，
if you want to know the sorted order,
如果您想知道排序顺序，
you do what's called an in-order traversal.
您执行所谓的有序遍历。
You look at a node.
您看一个节点。
You recursively visit the left child.
您递归访问左孩子。
Then you print out the root.
然后打印出根。
Then you recursively visit the right child.
然后，您递归地访问合适的孩子。
So in this case, we'd go left, left, print 11.
因此，在这种情况下，我们将向左，向左打印11。
Print 20.
打印20。
Go right.
向右走。
Go left.
向左走。
Print 26.
打印26。
Print 29.
打印29。
Go up.
上。
Print 41.
打印41。
Go right.
向右走。
Print 50.
打印50。
Print 65.
打印65。
Then check that's in sorted order.
然后检查它的排序顺序。
If you're not familiar with in-order traversal,
如果您不熟悉顺序遍历，
look at the textbook.
看课本。
It's a very simple operation.
这是一个非常简单的操作。
I'm not going to talk about it more here,
我在这里不再谈论它，
except we're going to use it.
除了我们要使用它。
All right, we'll get to the topic of today's lecture
好吧，我们将讨论今天的演讲主题
in a moment, which is balance.
一会儿，那是平衡。
What we saw in last lecture and recitation
我们在上一次讲座和朗诵中看到的
is that these basic binary search
是这些基本的二进制搜索
trees, where when you insert a node you just walk down
树木，当您插入节点时，您只需向下走
the tree to find where that item fits-- like if you're trying
找到适合的项目的树-就像您正在尝试
to insert 30, you go left here, go right here, go right here,
插入30，您在此处向左走，在此处向右走，在此处向右走，
and say, oh 30 fits here.
说，哦30适合这里。
Let's put 30 there.
让我们把30放在那里。
If you keep doing that, you can do insert.
如果继续这样做，则可以插入。
You can do delete.
您可以删除。
You can do these kinds of searches,
您可以进行此类搜索，
which we saw, finding the next larger element
我们看到了，找到了下一个更大的元素
or finding the next smaller element, also known
或寻找下一个较小的元素
as successor and predecessor.
作为继任者和前任。
These are actually the typical names for those operations.
这些实际上是这些操作的典型名称。
You can solve them in order h time.
您可以按h时间解决它们。
Anyone remember what h was?
有人记得h是什么吗？
The height.
高度。
Yeah, good.
耶，好样的。
The height of the tree.
树的高度。
So h is the height of the BST.
因此，h是BST的高度。
What is the height of the tree?
那棵树的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Log n?
教授：登录n？
Log n would be great, but not always.
Log n很好，但并非总是如此。
So this is the issue of being balance.
因此，这是保持平衡的问题。
So in an ideal world, your tree's
所以在理想的世界里，你的树是
going to look something like this.
看起来像这样
I've drawn this picture probably the most in my academic career.
这幅画可能是我职业生涯中最多的。
This is a nice, perfectly balanced binary search tree.
这是一个很好的，完美平衡的二进制搜索树。
The height is log n.
高度为log n。
This would be the balance case.
这将是平衡情况。
I mean, roughly log n.
我的意思是大致登录n。
Let's just put theta to be approximate.
让我们将θ近似。
But as we saw at the end of last class,
但是正如我们在上课结束时看到的那样，
you can have a very unbalanced tree, which is just a path.
您可以拥有非常不平衡的树，这只是一条路径。
And there the height is n.
高度为n。
What's the definition of height?
高度的定义是什么？
That's actually what I was looking for.
这实际上就是我想要的。
Should be 6.042 material.
应该是6.042的材质。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Is it the length of the longest path
听众：这是最长路径的长度吗
always going down?
总是下去？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, length of the longest path always going down.
教授：是的，最长的路径的长度总是下降。
So length of the longest path from the root to some leaf.
因此，是从根到叶的最长路径的长度。
That's right.
那就对了。
OK, so this is--
好的，这是-
I highlight this because we're going
我强调这一点，因为我们要
to be working a lot with height today.
今天要努力工作
All that's happening here, all of the paths are length log n.
这里发生的所有事情，所有路径都是length log n。
Here, there is a path of length n.
在此，存在长度为n的路径。
Some of them are shorter, but in fact, the average path
其中一些较短，但实际上，平均路径
is n over 2.
在2以上。
It's really bad.
真的很糟糕
So this is very unbalanced.
因此，这是非常不平衡的。
I'll put "very."
我会说“非常”。
It's not a very formal term, but that's
这不是一个非常正式的术语，但这是
like the worst case for BSTs.
例如BST的最坏情况。
This is good.
很好
This does have a formal definition.
这确实有一个正式定义。
We call a tree balanced if the height is order log n.
如果高度是阶数log n，我们称树为平衡的。
So you're storing n keys.
因此，您要存储n个键。
If your height is always order log n,
如果您的身高始终为log n，
we get a constant factor here.
我们在这里得到一个常数。
Here, it's basically exactly log n, 1 times log n.
在这里，基本上是log n，是log n的1倍。
It's always going to be at least log n,
总是至少要为log n，
because if you're storing n things in a binary tree,
因为如果您要在二叉树中存储n件事，
you need to have height at least log n.
您需要使高度至少为log n。
So in fact, it will be theta log n if your tree is balanced.
因此，实际上，如果您的树是平衡的，它将是theta log n。
And today's goal is to always maintain
今天的目标是始终保持
that your trees are balanced.
你的树木是平衡的。
And we're going to do that using the structure
我们将使用该结构
called AVL trees, which I'll define in a moment.
称为AVL树，稍后我将对其进行定义。
They're the original way people found
这是人们发现的原始方式
to keep trees balanced back in the '60s,
保持树木在60年代的平衡，
but they're still kind of the simplest.
但它们仍然是最简单的一种。
There are lots of ways to keep a tree balanced,
有很多方法可以使树保持平衡，
so I'll mention some other balance trees later on.
所以稍后我会提到其他一些平衡树。
In particular, your textbook covers two other ways to do it.
特别是，您的教科书涵盖了另外两种实现方法。
It does not cover AVL trees, so pay attention.
它不包括AVL树，因此请注意。
One more thing I wanted to define.
我想定义一件事。
We talked about the height of the tree,
我们谈到了树的高度，
but I'd also like to talk about the height of a node in a tree.
但我也想谈一谈树中节点的高度。
Can anyone define this for me?
谁能为我定义这个？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: It's the level that the node is at.
听众：这是节点所在的级别。
PROFESSOR: The level that the node is at.
教授：节点所在的级别。
That is roughly right.
大致正确。
I mean, that is right.
我的意思是，那是对的。
It's all about, what is the level of a node?
就是说，节点的级别是多少？
AUDIENCE: Like how many levels of children it has.
听众：就像有多少个孩子。
PROFESSOR: How many levels of children it has.
教授：它有多少个孩子等级。
That's basically right, yeah.
没错，是的。
AUDIENCE: The distance from it to the root.
听众：从它到根的距离。
PROFESSOR: Distance from it to the root.
教授：到根的距离。
That would be the depth.
那就是深度。
So depth is counting from above.
因此，深度是从上方算起的。
Height is--
身高是-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yes, longest path from that node to the leaf.
教授：是的，从该节点到叶子的最长路径。
Note that's why I wrote this definition actually,
请注意，这就是我实际上编写此定义的原因，
to give you a hint.
给你一个提示。
Here I should probably say down to be precise.
在这里我应该说清楚一点。
You're not allowed to go up in these paths.
您不允许沿着这些路径前进。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
All right.
好吧。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I've got to learn how to throw.
我必须学习如何投掷。
All right.
好吧。
So for example, over here I'm going to write depths in red.
因此，例如，在这里我将用红色书写深度。
If you're taking notes it's OK.
如果您要记笔记，可以。
Don't worry.
不用担心
So length off the longest path from it down to a leaf.
因此，要延长从它到叶子的最长路径。
Well, this is a leaf, so its height is 0.
好吧，这是一片叶子，因此其高度为0。
OK.
好。
Yeah, I'll just leave it at that.
是的，我只保留它。
It takes 0 steps to get from a leaf to a leaf.
从一片叶子到一片叶子需要0步。
This guy's not a leaf.
这个家伙不是一片叶子。
It has a child, but it has a path of length one to a leaf.
它有一个孩子，但是到叶子的长度为一。
So it's one.
所以这是一个。
This guy has a choice.
这个家伙有一个选择。
You could go left and you get a path of length 1,
您可以向左走，然后得到一条长度为1的路径
or you could go right and get a path of length 2.
否则您可以向右走并获得长度为2的路径。
We take the max, so this guy has height 2.
我们以最大值为准，所以这个人的身高为2。
This node has height 1.
该节点的高度为1。
This node has height 3.
该节点的高度为3。
How do you compute the height of a node?
您如何计算节点的高度？
Anyone?
任何人？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Max of the height of the children plus 1.
听众：孩子的身高上限加1。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
You take the max of the height of the children.
您将孩子的身高最大化。
Here, 2 and 1.
在这里2和1。
Max is 2.
最大值为2。
Add 1.
加1。
You get 3.
你得到3。
So it's going to always be-- this is just a formula.
因此，它将永远是-这只是一个公式。
The height of the left child maxed
左孩子的身高最大
with the height of the right child plus 1.
合适的孩子的身高加1。
This is obviously useful for computing.
这显然对计算很有用。
And in particular, in lecture and recitation
特别是在演讲和朗诵中
last time, we saw how to maintain
上次我们看到了如何保养
the size of every tree using data structure augmentation.
使用数据结构扩充的每棵树的大小。
Data structure augmentation.
数据结构扩充。
And then we started with a regular vanilla binary search
然后我们开始进行常规的原始二进制搜索
tree, and then we maintained-- every time
树，然后我们每次维护
we did an operation on the tree, we also
我们在树上做了一个手术，
updated the size of the subtree rooted
更新了植根的子树的大小
at that node, the size field.
在该节点上的size字段。
Here, I want to store a height field,
在这里，我想存储一个高度场，
and because I have this nice local rule that tells me
而且因为我有一条很好的当地法则告诉我
how to compute the height of a node using just
如何仅使用节点计算高度
local information-- the height of its left child, the height
当地信息-左孩子的身高，身高
of its right child.
正确的孩子
Do a constant amount of work here.
在这里做固定的工作。
There's a general theorem.
有一个一般性定理。
Whenever you have a nice local formula
只要您有一个不错的本地公式
like this for updating your information in terms
像这样更新您的信息
of your children, then you can maintain
的孩子，那么你可以维持
it using constant overhead.
它使用恒定的开销。
So we can store the height of every node for free.
因此，我们可以免费存储每个节点的高度。
Why do I care?
我为什么在乎？
Because AVL trees are going to use the heights of the nodes.
因为AVL树将使用节点的高度。
Our goal is to keep the heights small.
我们的目标是使身高保持较小。
We don't want this.
我们不想要这个。
We want this.
我们想要这个。
So a natural thing to do is store the heights.
因此，自然要做的就是存储高度。
When they get too big, fix it.
当它们太大时，请修复它。
So that's what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的。
Maybe one more thing to mention over here for convenience.
为了方便起见，也许在这里还要提一件事。
Leaves, for example, have children that are-- I mean,
举例来说，树叶的孩子是-我的意思是，
they have null pointers to their left and right children.
他们有指向左和右孩子的空指针。
You could draw them explicitly like this.
您可以像这样显式地绘制它们。
Also some nodes just lack a single child.
另外，有些节点只是缺少一个孩子。
I'm going to define the depths of these things
我将定义这些东西的深度
to be negative 1.
为负1。
This will be convenient later on.
以后会很方便。
Why negative 1?
为什么是负数1？
Because then this formula works.
因为此公式有效。
You can just think about it.
您可以考虑一下。
Like leaves, for example, have two children,
像树叶一样，有两个孩子，
which are negative 1.
都是负数1。
You take the max.
你拿最大。
You add 1.
您添加1。
You get 0.
您得到0。
So that just makes things work out.
这样就可以解决问题。
We don't normally draw these in the pictures,
我们通常不会在图片中画这些，
but it's convenient that I don't have to do special cases when
但是很方便，我不需要在特殊情况下
the left child doesn't exist and the right child doesn't exist.
左边的孩子不存在，右边的孩子不存在。
You could either do special cases
您可以做特殊情况
or you could make this definition.
或者您可以进行此定义。
Up to you.
由你决定。
OK.
好。
AVL trees.
AVL树。
So the idea with an AVL tree is the following.
因此，使用AVL树的想法如下。
We'd like to keep the height order log n.
我们想保持高度顺序为n。
It's a little harder to think about keeping the height order
考虑保持高度顺序有点困难
log n than it is to think about keeping the tree balance,
记录n而不是考虑保持树的平衡，
meaning the left and right sides are more or less equal.
表示左右两侧大致相等。
In this case, we're going to think about them
在这种情况下，我们将考虑它们
as being more or less equal in height.
高度大致相等
You could also think about them being
您也可以考虑他们是
more or less equal in subtree size.
子树大小大致相等。
That would also work.
那也可以。
It's a different balanced search tree.
这是不同的平衡搜索树。
Height is kind of the easiest thing to work with.
高度是最容易使用的一种方法。
So if we have a node, it has a left subtree.
因此，如果我们有一个节点，则它有一个左子树。
It has a right subtree, which we traditionally
它有一个正确的子树，我们传统上
draw as triangles.
画成三角形。
This subtree has a height.
该子树具有高度。
We'll call it HL for left.
我们将其称为HL。
By the height of the subtree, I mean the height of its root.
子树的高度是指其根的高度。
And the right subtree has some height, r.
右子树的高度为r。
I've drawn them as the same, but in general they
我把它们画得一样，但总的来说
might be different.
可能会有所不同。
And what we would like is that h sub l and h
我们想要的是h sub l和h
sub r are more or less the same.
sub r大致相同。
They differ by at most an additive 1.
它们最多相加1。
So if I look at h sub l minus h sub r in absolute value,
因此，如果我以绝对值看h sub l减去h sub r，
this is at most 1, for every node.
每个节点最多为1。
So I have some node x.
所以我有一些节点x。
For every node x, I want the left and right subtrees
对于每个节点x，我想要左右子树
to be almost balanced.
几乎达到平衡。
Now, I could say differ by at most 0,
现在，我可以说最多相差0，
that the left and right have exactly the same heights.
左右高度完全相同。
That's difficult, because that really
那很困难，因为那真的
forces you to have exactly the perfect tree.
迫使您拥有完美的树。
And in fact, it's not even possible for odd n or even n
实际上，甚至不可能有奇数n或什至n
or something.
或者其他的东西。
Because at the very end you're going
因为最后你要走
to have one missing child, and then you're unbalanced there.
怀有一个失踪的孩子，然后那里就不平衡了。
So 0's just not possible to maintain,
因此，就无法维持0，
but 1 is almost as good, hopefully.
但希望1几乎一样好。
We're going to prove that in a second.
我们将在一秒钟内证明这一点。
And it turns out to be easy to maintain in log n time.
而且事实证明，在登录前很容易维护。
So let's prove some stuff.
因此，让我们来证明一些东西。
So first claim is that AVL trees are balanced.
因此，第一个主张是AVL树是平衡的。
Balanced, remember, means that the height of them
记住，平衡意味着它们的高度
is always order log n.
始终是订单日志n。
So we're just going to assume for now that we can somehow
所以我们现在只是假设我们可以以某种方式
achieve this property.
实现此属性。
We want to prove that it implies that the height is
我们要证明它暗示高度为
at most some constant times log n.
最多恒定时间为log n。
We know it's at least log n, but also
我们知道至少是log n，但是
like it to be not much bigger.
希望它不会太大。
So what do you think is the worst case?
那么您认为最坏的情况是什么？
Say I have n nodes.
说我有n个节点。
How could I make the tree as high as possible?
我怎样才能使树尽可能高？
Or conversely, if I have a particular height,
或者相反，如果我有特定身高，
how could I make it have as few nodes as possible?
我如何使它具有尽可能少的节点？
That'd be like the sparsest, the least balanced
就像最稀疏，最不平衡
situation for AVL trees.
AVL树的情况。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: You could have one node on the last level.
听众：您可以在最后一个级别上有一个节点。
PROFESSOR: One node on the last level, yeah, in particular.
教授：尤其是最后一层上的一个节点。
Little more.
再多一点。
What do the other levels look like?
其他级别是什么样的？
That is correct, but I want to know the whole tree.
没错，但是我想知道整棵树。
It's hard to explain the tree, but you
很难解释这棵树，但是你
can explain the core property of the tree.
可以解释树的核心属性。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: For every node, let's make
教授：对于每个节点，让我们
the right side have a height of one larger than the left side.
右侧的高度比左侧大1。
I think that's worth a cushion.
我认为这值得缓冲。
See if I can throw better.
看看我能不能扔得更好。
Good catch.
接得好。
Better than hitting your eye.
总比打动你的眼睛好。
So I'm going to not prove this formally,
所以我不会正式证明这一点，
but I think if you stare at this long enough it's
但我想如果你凝视了足够长的时间
pretty obvious.
很明显。
Worst case is when-- there are multiple worst cases,
最坏的情况是：有多个最坏的情况，
because right and left are symmetric.
因为左右是对称的
We don't really care.
我们不在乎。
But let's say that the right subtree
但是，假设正确的子树
has height one more than the left for every node.
每个节点的高度都比左侧高。
OK, this is a little tricky to draw.
好的，这有点棘手。
Not even sure I want to try to draw it.
甚至不确定我是否想尝试绘制它。
But you basically draw it recursively.
但是您基本上是递归绘制的。
So, OK, somehow I've figured out this
好吧，以某种方式我已经弄清楚了
where the height difference here is 1.
这里的高度差是1。
Then I take two copies of it.
然后我拿了两份。
It's like a fractal.
这就像一个分形。
You should know all about fractals by now.
您现在应该了解分形。
Problem set two.
习题二。
And then you just-- well, that's not quite right.
然后您只是-嗯，那是不对的。
In fact, I need to somehow make this one a little
实际上，我需要以某种方式使它变一点
bit taller and then glue these together.
高一点，然后将它们粘在一起。
Little tricky.
有点棘手。
Let's not even try to draw the tree.
让我们甚至不要尝试绘制树。
Let's just imagine this is possible.
让我们想象一下这是可能的。
It is possible.
有可能的。
And instead, I'm going to use mathematics
相反，我将使用数学
to understand how high that tree is.
了解那棵树有多高。
Or actually, it's a little easier
或者实际上，这要容易一些
to think about-- let me get this right.
想一想-让我说对了。
It's so easy that I have to look at my notes
如此简单，我必须看一下笔记
to remember what to write.
记住要写些什么。
Really, no problem.
真的没问题
All right, so I'm going to define n sub h
好吧，所以我要定义n sub h
is the minimum number of nodes that's
是最小的节点数
possible in an AVL tree of height h.
可能在高度为h的AVL树中。
This is sort of the inverse of what we care about,
这与我们所关心的相反
but if we can solve the inverse, we can solve the thing.
但是如果我们能解决逆问题，我们就能解决问题。
What we really care about is, for n nodes, how large
我们真正关心的是，对于n个节点，有多大
can the height be?
高度可以吗？
We want to prove that's order log n.
我们想证明那是订单日志n。
But it'll be a lot easier to think about the reverse, which
但是考虑相反的情况会容易得多，
is, if I fix the height to be h, what's the fewest nodes
是，如果我将高度固定为h，那么最少的节点是多少
that I can pack in?
我可以打包吗？
Because for the very unbalanced tree, I have a height of n,
因为对于非常不平衡的树，我的高度为n，
and I only need to put n nodes.
而且我只需要放置n个节点。
That would be really bad.
那真的很糟糕。
What I prefer is a situation like this, where with height h,
我更喜欢这样的情况，高度为h，
I have to put in 2 to the h nodes.
我必须在h节点中放入2。
That would be perfect balance.
那将是完美的平衡。
Any constant to the h will do.
h的任何常数都可以。
So when you take the inverse, you get a log.
因此，当您求逆时，您会得到一个日志。
OK, we'll get to that in a moment.
好的，我们稍后再解决。
How should we analyze n sub h?
我们应该如何分析n sub h？
I hear something.
我听到了
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] 2 to the h minus 1 [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[音频不清晰] 2至h减1 [音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Maybe, but I don't think that will quite work out.
教授：也许吧，但我认为这不会完全解决。
Any-- yeah?
是的-是吗？
AUDIENCE: So you have only 1 node in the last level,
听众：所以您在最后一级只有一个节点，
so it would be 1/2 to the h plus 1.
所以它是h加1的1/2。
PROFESSOR: That turns out to be approximately correct,
教授：事实证明这是正确的，
but I don't know where you got 1/2 to the h plus 1.
但我不知道你的h加1等于1/2。
It's not exactly correct.
这不是完全正确。
I'll tell you that, so that your analysis isn't right.
我告诉你，这样你的分析是不正确的。
It's a lot easier.
这要容易得多。
You guys are worried about the last level
你们担心最后的水平
and actually what the tree looks like, but in fact, all you need
实际上是树的样子，但是实际上，您需要的一切
is this.
这是。
All you need is love, yeah.
是的，您需要的只是爱。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: No, it's not a half.
教授：不，不是一半。
It's a different constant.
这是一个不同的常数。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Start with base cases and write a recursive formula.
听众：从基本案例开始，然后编写一个递归公式。
PROFESSOR: Ah, recursive formula.
教授：啊，递归公式。
Good.
好。
You said start with base cases.
您说的是从基本案例开始的。
I always forget that part, so it's good that you remember.
我总是忘记那部分，所以记住你是件好事。
You should start with the base case,
您应该从基本情况开始，
but I'm not going to worry about the base case
但我不会担心基本情况
because it won't matter.
因为没关系。
Because I know the base case is always going to be n order 1
因为我知道基本情况总是n阶1
is order 1.
是订单1。
So for algorithms, that's usually all
因此，对于算法，通常就是全部
you need for base case, but it's good that you think about it.
您需要基本情况​​，但考虑一下是很好的。
What I was looking for is recursive formula,
我一直在寻找递归公式，
aka, recurrence.
aka，复发。
So can someone tell me-- maybe even you-- could tell me
有人可以告诉我-甚至您-可以告诉我
a recurrence for n sub h, in terms of n sub smaller h?
n sub h的递归，用n sub较小的h表示？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: 1 plus [INAUDIBLE].
听众：1加[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: 1 plus n sub h minus 1.
教授：1加n减去h减1。
Not quite.
不完全的。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: N sub h minus 1 plus n sub h minus 2.
听众：N sub h减去1加n sub h减去2。
PROFESSOR: N plus-- do you want the 1 plus?
教授：N加-您要加1吗？
AUDIENCE: I don't think so.
听众：我不这么认为。
PROFESSOR: You do.
教授：可以。
It's a collaboration.
这是一种协作。
To combine your two answers, this
为了结合您的两个答案，这
should be the correct formula.
应该是正确的公式。
Let me double check.
让我仔细检查一下。
Yes, whew.
是的，哇。
Good.
好。
OK, why?
好为什么
Because the one thing we know is that our tree looks like this.
因为我们知道的一件事是我们的树看起来像这样。
The total height here is h.
这里的总高度是h。
That's what we're trying to figure out.
这就是我们试图找出的。
How many nodes are in this tree of height h?
在这棵高度为h的树中有多少个节点？
Well, the height is the max of the two directions.
好吧，高度是两个方向的最大值。
So that means that the larger has height h minus 1,
因此，这意味着较大者的身高h减去1，
because the longest path to a leaf
因为通往叶子的最长路径
is going to be down this way.
这样下去。
What's the height of this?
这个高度是多少？
Well, it's one less than the height of this.
好吧，这比这个高度少一。
So it's going to be h minus 2.
所以它将是h减2。
This is where the n sub h minus 1 plus n sub h minus 2 come in.
这是n sub h减去1加n sub h减去2的地方。
But there's also this node.
但是也有这个节点。
It doesn't actually make a big difference in this recurrence.
实际上，这种复发没有太大的区别。
This is the exponential part.
这是指数部分。
This is like itty bitty thing.
这就像小小的可怜的事情。
But it matters for the base case is pretty much
但这对基本情况很重要
where it matters.
重要的地方。
Back to your base case.
回到您的基本情况。
There's one guy here, plus all the nodes on the left,
这里有一个人，加上左边的所有节点，
plus all the nodes on the right.
加上右边的所有节点。
And for whatever reason, I put the left
而无论出于什么原因，我把左边的
over here and the right over here.
在这里，就在这里
And of course, you could reverse this picture.
当然，您可以反转此图。
It doesn't really matter.
没关系。
You get the same formula.
您得到相同的公式。
That's the point.
这才是重点。
So this is the recurrence.
所以这就是复发。
Now we need to solve it.
现在我们需要解决它。
What we would like is for it to be exponential,
我们希望它是指数的，
because that means there's a lot of nodes in a height h AVL
因为那意味着高度为AVL的节点很多
tree.
树。
So any suggestions on how we could figure out
因此，关于如何找出答案的任何建议
this recurrence?
这种复发？
Does it look like anything you've seen before?
它看起来像您以前见过的任何东西吗？
AUDIENCE: Fibonacci.
观众：斐波那契。
PROFESSOR: Fibonacci.
教授：斐波那契。
It's almost Fibonacci.
差不多是斐波那契。
If I hid this plus 1, which you wanted to do,
如果我隐藏了您想要做的加号1，
then it would be exactly Fibonacci.
那就恰好是斐波那契
Well, that's actually good, because in particular, n sub h
嗯，那实际上很好，因为特别是n sub h
is bigger than Fibonacci.
比斐波那契更大。
If you add one at every single level,
如果您在每个级别添加一个，
the certainly you get something bigger
当然可以得到更大的东西
than the base Fibonacci sequence.
比基本斐波那契数列
Now, hopefully you know Fibonacci is exponential.
现在，希望您知道斐波那契是指数的。
I have an exact formula.
我有一个确切的公式。
If you take the golden ratio to the power h, divide by root 5,
如果将黄金比例乘以幂h，则除以根5，
and round to the nearest integer,
并四舍五入到最接近的整数，
you get exactly the Fibonacci number.
您将确切地得到斐波那契数。
Crazy stuff.
疯狂的事情。
We don't need to know why that's true.
我们不需要知道为什么是这样。
Just take it as fact.
只是把它当作事实。
And conveniently phi is bigger than 1.
方便地，phi大于1。
You don't need to remember what phi
您无需记住什么phi
is, except it is bigger than 1.
是，但大于1。
And so this is an exponential bound.
因此，这是指数范围。
This is good news.
这是个好消息。
So I'll tell you it's about 1.618.
所以我告诉你大约是1.618。
And so we get is that-- if we invert this,
所以我们得到的是-如果我们将其反转，
this says n sub h is bigger than some phi to the h.
这表示n sub h大于h的phi。
This is our n, basically.
基本上这就是我们的n
What we really want to know is how
我们真正想知道的是
h relates to n, which is just inverting this formula.
h与n有关，后者只是将这个公式求逆。
So we have, on the other hand, the phi
因此，另一方面，
to the h divided by root 5 is less than n.
到h除以根5的值小于n。
So I got a log base phi on both sides.
所以我两边都得到了对数基phi。
Seems like a good thing to do.
似乎是一件好事。
This is actually quite annoying.
这实际上很烦人。
I've got h minus a tiny little thing.
我有h减去一件小事。
It's less than log base phi of n.
它小于n的对数底phi。
And I will tell you that is about 1.440 times log base 2
我会告诉你，这是对数基数2的1.440倍
of n, because after all, log base 2 is what computer
之所以是n，是因为毕竟日志基数2是什么计算机
scientists care about.
科学家们在乎。
So just to put it into perspective.
因此，只是将其放在透视图中。
We want it to be theta log base 2 of n.
我们希望它成为n的theta日志基数2。
And here's the bound.
这就是界限。
The height is always less than 1.44 times log n.
高度始终小于log n的1.44倍。
All we care about is some constant,
我们所关心的只是一个常数，
but this is a pretty good constant.
但这是一个很好的常数。
We'd like one.
我们想要一个。
There are binary search tress that achieve 1, plus very,
有二进制搜索树可以达到1，而且非常好，
very tiny thing, arbitrarily tiny, but this is pretty good.
非常微小的东西，任意微小，但这很好。
Now, if you don't know Fibonacci numbers,
现在，如果您不知道斐波那契数，
I pull a rabbit out of a hat and I've got this phi to the h.
我从帽子中拉出一只兔子，然后把这个phi带到了h。
It's kind of magical.
有点神奇。
There's a much easier way to analyze this recurrence.
有一种更简单的方法来分析这种复发。
I'll just tell you because it's good to know but not
我只是告诉你，因为很高兴知道
super critical.
超临界。
So we have this recurrence, n sub h.
因此，我们有n个子h重复出现。
This is the computer scientist way to solve the recurrence.
这是解决重复问题的计算机科学家方法。
We don't care about the constants.
我们不在乎常量。
This is the theoretical computer scientist
这是理论计算机科学家
way to solve this recurrence.
解决这种复发的方法。
We don't care about constants.
我们不在乎常量。
And so we say, aw, this is hard.
所以我们说，噢，这很难。
I've got n sub h minus 1 and n sub h minus 2.
我得到n sub h减去1和n sub h减去2。
So asymmetric.
如此不对称。
Let's symmetrify.
让我们对称。
Could I make them both n sub h minus 1.
我可以将它们都设为n sub h减去1。
Or could I make them both n sub h minus 2?
还是可以让它们都减去n减去2？
Suggestions?
有什么建议吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Minus 2 is the right way
教授：减法2是正确的方法
to go because I want to know n sub h is greater than something
去，因为我想知道n sub h大于某物
in order to get a less than down here.
为了得到比这里少的东西。
By the way, I use that log is monatomic here,
顺便说一下，我在这里使用的日志是单原子的，
but it is, so we're good.
但这是事实，所以我们很好。
So this is going to be greater than 1
所以这将大于1
plus 2 times n sub h minus 2.
加2乘以n sub h减去2。
Because if I have a larger height
因为如果我身高更大
I'm going to have more nodes.
我将有更多的节点。
That's an easy proof by induction.
通过归纳法，这很容易证明。
So I can combine these into one term.
所以我可以将它们合并为一个术语。
It's simpler.
更简单。
I can get rid of this 1 because that only makes things bigger.
我可以摆脱这个1，因为那只会使事情变大。
So I just have this.
所以我只有这个。
OK, now I need a base case, but this
好，现在我需要一个基本情况，但这
looks like 2 the something.
看起来像2的东西。
What's the something?
什么事
H over 2.
超过2。
So I'll just write theta to avoid the base case.
因此，我只写theta以避免基本情况。
2 to the h over 2.
2到h 2。
Every two steps of h, I get another factor of 2.
h每隔两步，我得到另一个因子2。
So when you invert and do the log,
因此，当您反转并进行记录时，
this means that h is also less than log base 2 of n.
这意味着h也小于n的对数底数2。
Log base 2 because of that.
因此，请记录基数2。
Factor 2 out here because of that factor 2
由于该因子2而将因子2排除在这里
when you take the log.
当您记录日志时。
And so the real answer is 1.44.
因此，真正的答案是1.44。
This is the correct-- this is the worst case.
没错-这是最坏的情况。
But it's really easy to prove that it's, at most, 2 log n.
但是很容易证明它最多为2 log n。
So keep this in mind in case we ask
所以请记住这一点，以防我们问
you to analyze variance of AVL trees,
您分析AVL树的方差，
like in problem set three.
像问题三。
This is the easy way to do it and just get
这是做到这一点的简单方法
some constant times log n.
一些恒定时间记录n。
Clear?
明确？
All right, so that's AVL trees, why they're balanced.
好吧，这就是AVL树，为什么它们很平衡。
And so if we can achieve this property,
因此，如果我们可以实现此属性，
that the left and right subtrees have about the same height,
左右子树的高度大约相同，
we'll be done.
我们会完成的。
So how the heck do we maintain that property?
那么，我们如何维护该财产呢？
Let's go over here.
让我们过去吧。
Mobius trees are supposed to support
莫比乌斯树应该支持
a whole bunch of operations, but in particular, insert
一堆操作，但特别是插入
and delete.
并删除。
I'm just going to worry about insert today.
我只是担心今天插入。
Delete is almost identical.
删除几乎相同。
And it's in the code that corresponds to this lecture,
它是在与本讲座相对应的代码中，
so you can take a look at it.
所以你可以看看它。
Very, very similar.
非常非常相似。
Let's start with insert.
让我们从插入开始。
Well, it's pretty straightforward.
好吧，这很简单。
Our algorithm is as follows.
我们的算法如下。
We do the simple BST insertion, which we already saw,
我们已经完成了简单的BST插入，
which is you walk down the tree to find where that key fits.
您是在树上走下来找到适合钥匙的地方。
You search for that key.
您搜索该密钥。
And wherever it isn't, you insert a node there,
不管它不在哪里，您都可以在其中插入一个节点，
insert a new leaf, and add it in.
插入新的叶子，并将其添加。
Now, this will not preserve the AVL property.
现在，这将不会保留AVL属性。
So the second step is fix the AVL property.
因此，第二步是修复AVL属性。
And there's a nice concise description of AVL insertion.
并且有一个很好的简洁的AVL插入描述。
Of course, how do you do step two is the interesting part.
当然，您如何做第二步是有趣的部分。
All right, maybe let's start with an example.
好吧，也许让我们从一个例子开始。
That could be fun.
那可能很有趣。
Hey, look, here's an example.
嘿，看，这是一个例子。
And to match the notes, I'm going
为了匹配音符，我要
to do insert 23 as a first example.
做插入23作为第一个示例。
OK, I'm also going to annotate this tree a little bit.
好的，我还要对这棵树进行一些注释。
So I said we store the heights, but what
所以我说我们存储高度，但是
I care about is which height is larger, the left or the right.
我关心的是哪个高度更大，向左还是向右。
In fact, you could just store that,
实际上，您可以将其存储起来，
just store whether it's plus 1, minus 1,
只需存储是否加1减1
or 0, the difference between left and right sides.
或0，左右两边之差。
So I'm going to draw that with a little icon, which
所以我要画一个小图标
is a left arrow, a descending left arrow if this
是左箭头，如果是
is the bigger side.
是更大的一面。
And this is a right arrow.
这是向右箭头。
This is even.
这是偶数。
Left and right are the same.
左右是相同的。
Here, the left is heavier, or higher, I guess.
我猜这里的左边更重或更重。
Here it's even.
在这里，甚至。
Here it's left.
剩下来了
This is AVL, because it's only one
这是AVL，因为它只是一个
heavier wherever I have an arrow.
不管我有箭在哪里
OK, now I insert 23.
好，现在我插入23。
23 belongs-- it's less than 41, greater than 20, less than 29,
23属于-小于41，大于20，小于29，
less than 26.
少于26。
So it belongs here.
所以它属于这里。
Here's 23, a brand-new node.
这是23，一个全新的节点。
OK, now all the heights change.
好吧，现在所有的高度都在变化。
And it's annoying to draw what the heights are,
绘制高度是很烦人的，
but I'll do it.
但我会做。
This one changes to 1.
这变成1。
This is 0.
这是0。
This changes to 2.
更改为2。
This changes to 3.
更改为3。
This changes to 4.
更改为4。
Anyway, never mind what the heights are.
无论如何，不​​要介意身高是多少。
What's bad is, well, this guy's even.
不好的是，这个家伙甚至。
This guy's left heavy.
这个家伙很重。
This guy's now doubly left heavy.
这个家伙现在双倍沉重。
Bad news.
坏消息。
OK, let's not worry about above that.
好吧，让我们不必担心以上问题。
Let's just start.
让我们开始吧。
The algorithm is going to walk up the tree
算法要走到树上
and say, oh, when do I get something bad?
然后说，哦，什么时候变坏？
So now I have 23, 26, 29 in a path.
现在我的路径中有23、26、29。
I'd like to fix it.
我想修复它。
Hmm, how to fix it?
嗯，如何解决？
I don't think we know how to fix it, so I will tell you how.
我认为我们不知道该如何解决，因此我将告诉您如何解决。
Actually, I wasn't here last week.
其实上周我不在这里。
So did we cover rotations?
那么我们涵盖了轮换吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: OK, good.
教授：好的，很好。
Then you don't know.
那你不知道。
Let me tell you about rotations.
让我告诉您有关轮换的内容。
Super cool.
超酷。
It's just a tool.
这只是一个工具。
That's x and y.
那是x和y。
I always get these mixed up.
我总是把这些混在一起。
So this is called left rotate of x.
因此，这称为x的左旋转。
OK, so here's the thing we can do with binary search trees.
好的，这就是二进制搜索树可以做的事情。
It's like the only thing you need to know.
这就像您需要知道的唯一一件事。
Because you've got search in binary search trees
因为您已经在二叉搜索树中进行搜索
and you've got rotations.
而且你有轮换。
So when I have a tree like this, I've highlighted two nodes,
因此，当我有一棵这样的树时，我突出显示了两个节点，
and then there's the children hanging off of them.
然后有孩子挂在他们旁边。
Some of these might be empty, but they're trees,
其中一些可能是空的，但它们是树，
so we draw them as triangles.
因此我们将它们绘制为三角形。
If I just do this, which is like changing
如果我只是这样做，那就像改变
which is higher, x or y, and whatever the parent of x was
x或y较高，并且x的父级是
becomes the parent of y.
成为y的父代。
And vice versa, in fact.
反之亦然，实际上。
The parent of y was x, and now the parent of x is y.
y的父是x，现在x的父是y。
OK, the parent of a is still x.
OK，a的父代仍然是x。
The parent of b changes.
b的父代更改。
It used to be y.
过去是y。
Now it's x.
现在是x。
The parent of c was y.
c的父是y。
It's still y.
还是y。
So in a constant number of pointer changes,
因此，在恒定数量的指针更改中，
I can go from this to this.
我可以从这个转到这个。
This is constant time.
这是恒定的时间。
And more importantly, it satisfies the BST order
更重要的是，它满足BST顺序
property.
属性。
If you do an in-order traversal of this,
如果您对此进行有序遍历，
you will get a, x, b, y, c.
您将得到a，x，b，y，c。
If I do an in-order traversal over here, I get a, x, b, y, c.
如果我在此处进行有序遍历，则得到a，x，b，y，c。
So they're the same.
所以他们是一样的。
So it still has BST ordering.
因此它仍然具有BST排序。
You can check more formally.
您可以进行更正式的检查。
b has all the nodes between x and y.
b具有x和y之间的所有节点。
Still all the nodes between x and y, and so on.
仍然是x和y之间的所有节点，依此类推。
You can check it at home, but this works.
您可以在家检查它，但是可以。
We call it a left rotate because the root moves to the left.
我们称其为左旋转，因为根部向左移动。
You can go straight back where you came from.
您可以直接回到原籍。
This would be a right rotate of y.
这将是y的右旋。
OK, it's a reversible operation.
好，这是可逆的操作。
It lets you manipulate the tree.
它使您可以操纵树。
So when we have this picture and we're
所以当我们有了这张照片，我们
really sad because this looks like a mess, what
真的很伤心，因为这看起来像一团糟，
we'd like to do is fix it.
我们要做的就是修复它。
This is a path of three nodes.
这是三个节点的路径。
We'd really prefer it to look like this.
我们真的希望它看起来像这样。
If we could make that transformation, we'd be happy.
如果我们能够进行这种转变，我们将很高兴。
And we can.
而且我们可以。
It is a right rotate of 29.
向右旋转29。
So that's what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的。
So let me quickly copy.
因此，让我快速复制。
I want to rotate 29 to the right, which
我想向右旋转29
means 29 and 26-- this is x.
表示29和26-这是x。
This is y.
这是y。
I turn them, and so I get 26 here now,
我打开它们，所以我现在得到26，
and 29 is the new right child.
29是新的合适的孩子。
And then whatever was the left child
然后剩下的那个孩子
of x becomes the left child of x in the picture.
的x成为图片中x的左孩子。
You can check it.
您可以检查一下。
So this used to be the triangle a.
因此，这曾经是三角形a。
And in this case, it's just the node 23.
在这种情况下，它只是节点23。
And we are happy.
我们很高兴。
Except I didn't draw the whole tree.
除了我没有画整棵树。
Now we're happy because we have an AVL tree again.
现在我们很高兴，因为我们又有了一棵AVL树。
Good news.
好消息。
So just check.
因此，请检查。
This is even.
这是偶数。
This is right heavy.
这很重。
This is even.
这是偶数。
This is left heavy still.
这仍然沉重。
This is left heavy, even, even, even.
这是沉重的，甚至，甚至，甚至。
OK, so now we have an AVL tree and our beauty is restored.
好，现在我们有了一棵AVL树，我们的美丽得以恢复。
I'll do one more example.
我再举一个例子。
Insert 55.
插入55。
We want to insert 55 here.
我们要在此处插入55。
And what changes is now this is even.
而且现在的变化是均匀的。
This is right heavy.
这很重。
This is doubly left heavy.
这加倍了。
We're super sad.
我们很伤心。
And then we don't look above that until later.
然后，直到稍后，我们才将其放在上面。
This is more annoying, because you
这更令人讨厌，因为您
look at this thing, this little path.
看这东西，这条小路。
It's a zigzag path, if you will.
如果可以的话，这是曲折的路径。
If I do a right rotation where this is x and this
如果我在这是x和这个的位置进行右旋转
is y, what I'll get is x, y, and then this is b.
是y，我得到的是x，y，然后是b。
This is what's in between x and y.
这就是x和y之间的值。
And so it'll go here.
因此，它将去这里。
And now it's a zag zig path, which is no better.
现在这是一个曲折的曲折路径，这再好不过了。
The height's the same.
高度相同。
And we're sad.
我们很伤心。
I told you, though, that somehow rotations
不过我告诉过你
are all we need to do.
这就是我们要做的。
What can I do?
我能做什么？
How could I fix this little zigzag?
我该如何修复这个小字形？
Just need to think about those three nodes,
只需要考虑这三个节点，
but all I give you are rotations.
但我给你的只是轮换。
AUDIENCE: Perhaps rotate 50.
听众：也许旋转50。
PROFESSOR: Maybe rotate 50.
教授：也许旋转50。
That seems like a good idea.
这似乎是个好主意。
Let's try it.
让我们尝试一下。
If you don't mind, I'm just going to write 41,
如果您不介意，我只会写41
and then there's all the stuff on the left.
然后左边有所有东西。
Now we rotate 50.
现在我们旋转50。
So 65 remains where it is.
因此，现在仍然有65个位置。
And we rotate 50 to the left.
然后我们向左旋转50。
So 50 and its child.
所以50和它的孩子。
This is x.
这是x。
This is y.
这是y。
And so I get 55 and I get 50.
所以我得到55，而我得到50。
Now, this is bad from an AVL perspective.
现在，从AVL角度来看，这是不好的。
This is still doubly left heavy, this is left heavy,
这仍然是双重的沉重，这仍然是沉重的，
and this is even.
这是偶数
But it looks like this case.
但是看起来像这种情况。
And so now I can do a right rotation on 65,
所以现在我可以对65度进行右旋转
and I will get-- so let me order the diagrams here.
我会得到的-所以让我在这里订购图表。
I do a right rotate on 65, and I will get 41.
我在65处进行右旋转，我会得到41。
And to the right I get 55.
右边是55。
And to the right I get 65.
右边是65。
To the left I get 50.
左边是50。
And then I get the left subtree.
然后我得到了左子树。
And so now this is even, even, even.
所以现在这是偶数，偶数，偶数。
Wow.
哇。
How high was left subtree?
剩下的子树有多高？
I think it's still left heavy.
我认为它仍然很重。
Cool.
凉。
This is what some people call double rotation,
这就是某些人所说的双向旋转
but I like to call it two rotations.
但我喜欢称之为两次轮换。
It's whatever you prefer.
随便你。
It's not really a new operation.
这不是真正的新操作。
It's just doing two rotations.
它只是做两个旋转。
So that's an example.
这就是一个例子。
Let's do the general case.
让我们来做一个一般的例子。
It's no harder.
没什么难的。
You might say, oh, gosh, why do you do two examples?
您可能会说，哦，天哪，为什么要举两个例子？
Well, because they were different.
好吧，因为它们是不同的。
And they're are two cases on the algorithm.
这是算法的两种情况。
You need to know both of them.
您需要了解他们两个。
OK, so AVL insert.
OK，所以插入AVL。
Here we go.
开始了。
Fix AVL property.
修复AVL属性。
I'm just going to call this from the changed node up.
我只是从更改后的节点开始调用它。
So the one thing that's missing from these examples
因此，这些示例中缺少的一件事
is that you might have to do more than two rotations.
是您可能必须做两次以上的旋转。
What we did was look at the lowest violation of the AVL
我们所做的是查看对AVL的最低违反
property and we fixed it.
财产，我们将其修复。
When we do that, there's still may
当我们这样做时，仍然可能
be violations higher up, because when you add a node,
是更高级别的违规，因为当您添加节点时，
you change the height of this subtree,
您更改此子树的高度，
the height of this subtree, the height of this subtree,
这个子树的高度，这个子树的高度，
and the height of this subtree, potentially.
以及该子树的高度。
What happened in these cases when I was done,
在这些情况下，当我做完了之后，
what I did fixed one violation.
我所做的解决了一个违规问题。
They were all fixed.
他们都是固定的。
But in general, there might be several violations up the tree.
但总的来说，树上可能存在一些违规情况。
So that's what we do.
这就是我们要做的。
Yeah, I'll leave it at that.
是的，我会保留它。
So suppose x is the lowest node that is not AVL.
因此，假设x是不是AVL的最低节点。
The way we find that node is we start at the node
找到该节点的方式是从该节点开始
that we changed.
我们改变了。
We check if that's OK.
我们检查是否可以。
We update the heights as we go up using our simple rule.
我们使用简单的规则在上升时更新高度。
And that's actually not our simple rule, but it's erased.
这实际上不是我们的简单规则，但是已被删除。
We update the height based on the heights of its children.
我们根据其子代的高度更新高度。
And you keep walking up until you
然后你一直走直到你
see, oh, the left is twice, two times-- or not two times,
哦，左边是两次，两次-或不是两次，
but plus 2 larger than the left, or vice versa.
但比左边大2，反之亦然。
Then you say, oh, that's bad.
然后你说，哦，那很不好。
And so we fix it.
因此，我们对其进行了修复。
Yeah, question.
是的，问题。
AUDIENCE: So here we continue to [INAUDIBLE].
听众：所以在这里我们继续[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
add n to the level [INAUDIBLE] than 1.
将n加到[音频不清晰]等级上，而不是1。
So add [INAUDIBLE].
因此，添加[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: AVL property's not about levels.
教授：AVL属性与级别无关。
It's about left subtrees and right subtrees.
它是关于左子树和右子树的。
So the trouble is that 65-- you have a left subtree, which
所以麻烦是65-您有一个左子树，
has height 2-- or sorry, height 1, I guess--
身高为2-或抱歉，身高为1-
because the longest path from here to a leaf is 1.
因为从这里到叶子的最长路径是1。
The right subtree has height negative 1
右子树的高度为负1
because it doesn't exist.
因为它不存在。
So it's one versus negative 1.
因此，它是一对负1。
So that's why there's a double arrow.
这就是为什么有一个双箭头。
Yeah, good to ask.
是的，很好问。
It's weird with the negative 1s.
负1怪异。
That's also why I wanted to define those negative 1s to be
这就是为什么我想将那些负1定义为
there, so the AVL property is easier to state.
在那里，因此AVL属性更易于陈述。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好吧。
Good.
好。
I think I want a symmetry assumption here.
我想在这里要一个对称的假设。
I don't know why I wrote right of x.
我不知道为什么我写x的权利。
I guess in modern days we write x dot right.
我猜想在现代，我们会在右边写x点。
Same thing.
一样。
OK, I'm going to assume that the right child is the heavier
好吧，我假设合适的孩子较重
one like we did before.
一个像我们以前做的。
Could be the left.
可能是左边。
It's symmetric.
它是对称的。
It doesn't matter.
没关系
So now there are two cases, like I said.
所以现在有两种情况，就像我说的那样。
I'm going to use this term right heavy
我要用这个词很重
because it's super convenient.
因为它超级方便。
OK, right heavy is what I've been
好吧，我一直很沉重
drawing by a descending right arrow.
用向下的向右箭头绘制。
Balance is what I've been drawing by a horizontal line.
平衡是我一直在画的水平线。
OK, so we're just distinguishing between these two cases.
好的，所以我们只区分这两种情况。
This turns out to be the easy case.
事实证明这很简单。
So we have x, y, a, b, c.
因此我们有x，y，a，b，c。
Why are we looking at the right child?
我们为什么要看合适的孩子？
Because we assumed that the right one is higher, so that x
因为我们假设正确的一个较高，所以x
was right heavy.
是沉重的。
So this subtree as I've drawn it is higher than the left one
所以我绘制的这棵子树比左边的树高
by 2, in fact.
减2，实际上。
And what we do in this case is right rotate of x.
在这种情况下，我们要做的是x的右旋转。
And so we get x, y, a, b, c.
这样我们得到x，y，a，b，c。
I could have drawn this no matter what case we're in,
不管我们在什么情况下我都可以画这个
so we need to check this actually works.
因此我们需要检查它是否确实有效。
That's the interesting part.
那是有趣的部分。
And that's over here.
在那边。
OK, so I said x is right heavy, in fact doubly so.
好的，所以我说x很重，实际上是双重的。
y is either right heavy or balanced.
y要么很重，要么平衡。
Let's start with right heavy.
让我们从权重开始。
So when we do this rotation, what happens to the heights?
因此，当我们进行旋转时，高度会发生什么？
Well, it's hard to tell.
好吧，这很难说。
It's a lot easier to think about what the actual heights are
考虑实际高度要容易得多
than just these arrows.
不仅仅是这些箭头。
So let's suppose x has height k.
因此，假设x的高度为k。
That's pretty generic.
那是很普通的。
And it's right heavy, so that means
而且很重，所以这意味着
the y has height k minus 1.
y的高度k减去1。
And then this is right heavy, so this has height k minus 2.
然后这很重，所以它的高度k减去2。
And this is something smaller then k minus 2.
这比k减去2小一些。
In fact, because this is AVL, we assume
实际上，因为这是AVL，我们假设
that x was the lowest that is not AVL.
x是不是AVL的最低值。
So y is AVL.
y是AVL。
And so this is going to be k minus 3,
所以这将是k减3，
and this is going to be k minus 3 because these differ by 2.
这将是k减去3，因为它们相差2。
You can prove by a simple induction you never
您可以通过简单的归纳证明您从未
get more than 2 out of whack because we're just adding 1,
从中获得超过2的收益，因为我们只增加1，
off by 1.
减1。
So we got off by 2.
所以我们到了2点下车。
So this is the bad situation.
所以这是糟糕的情况。
Now we can just update the heights over here.
现在我们可以更新这里的高度。
So k minus 3 for a, k minus 3 for b, k minus 2 for c.
因此，a的k减3，b的k减3，c的k减2。
Those don't change because we didn't touch those trees,
那些不会改变，因为我们没有碰到那些树，
and height is about going down, not up.
高度是下降而不是上升。
And so this becomes k minus 2, and this becomes k minus 1.
所以这变成k减去2，这变成k减去1。
And so we changed the height of the root,
因此，我们更改了根的高度，
but now you can see that life is good.
但现在您可以看到生活是美好的。
This is now balanced between k minus 3 and k minus 3.
现在，它在k负3和k负3之间平衡。
This is now balanced between k minus 2 and k minus 2.
现在，它在k负2和k负2之间平衡。
And now the parent of y may be messed up,
现在y的父母可能被搞砸了，
and that's why after this we go to the parent of y,
这就是为什么之后我们转到y的父级，
see if it's messed up, but keep working our way up.
看看是否搞砸了，但请继续努力。
But it worked.
但这行得通。
And in the interest of time, I will not
为了节省时间，我不会
check the case where y is balanced,
检查y是否平衡的情况，
but it works out, too.
但是也可以。
And see the notes.
并查看注释。
So the other case is where we do two rotations.
因此，另一种情况是我们进行两次旋转。
And in general, so here x was doubly right heavy.
总的来说，这里的x非常重。
And the else case is when the right child
否则的情况是合适的孩子
of x, which I'm going to call z here, is left heavy.
x的值（这里我将其称为z）很重。
That's the one remaining situation.
那是剩下的一种情况。
You do the same thing, and you check
您做同样的事情，然后检查
that right rotating and left rotating, which
右旋转和左旋转，
makes the nice picture, which is x, y, z,
制作漂亮的图片，它是x，y，z，
actually balances everything and you restore the AVL property.
实际上平衡了所有内容，并且您恢复了AVL属性。
So again, check the notes on that.
因此，再次检查该注释。
I have a couple minutes left, and instead I'd
我还剩几分钟，相反，我会
like to tell you a little bit about how
想告诉您一些有关
this fits into big-picture land.
这适合大片土地。
Two things I want to talk about.
我想谈两件事。
One is you could use this, of course,
一个是您当然可以使用
to sort, which is, if you want to sort n numbers,
进行排序，也就是说，如果您要对n个数字进行排序，
you insert them and you do in-order traversal.
您插入它们并进行有序遍历。
How long does this take?
这需要多长时间？
In-order traversal takes linear time.
有序遍历需要线性时间。
That's the sense in which we're storing things in sorted order.
这就是我们按排序顺序存储事物的意义。
Inserting n items-- well, each insert takes h time,
插入n项-嗯，每次插入需要h时间，
but now we're guaranteed that h is order log n.
但是现在我们保证h是订单日志n。
So all the insertions take log n time each, n log n total.
因此，所有插入操作每次花费log n次，总共花费n log n次。
So this is yet another way to sort n items in n log n time,
所以这是另一种在n log n时间内对n个项目进行排序的方法，
in some ways the most powerful way.
在某些方面是最强大的方式。
We've seen heaps, and we've seen merge sort.
我们已经看到了堆，也看到了合并排序。
They all sort.
他们都排序。
Heaps let you do two operations, insert and delete min, which
堆让您执行两项操作，即插入和删除最小值，其中
a lot of times is all you care about, like in p set two.
很多时候就是您所关心的，例如在第二组中。
But these guys, AVL trees, let you
但是这些家伙，AVL树，让您
do insert, delete, and delete min.
插入，删除和删除最小值。
So they're the same in those senses,
所以它们在这些意义上是相同的，
but we have the new operation, which
但是我们有新的操作
is that we can do find next larger and next smaller, aka
是我们可以找到下一个更大和另一个较小的
successor and predecessor.
后继者和前任者。
So you can think about what we call an abstract data type.
因此，您可以考虑一下我们所谓的抽象数据类型。
These are the operations that you support,
这些是您支持的操作，
or that you're supposed to support.
还是您应该支持的。
If you're into Java, you call this an interface.
如果您喜欢Java，可以将其称为接口。
But this is an algorithmic specification
但这是一个算法规范
of what your data structure is supposed to do.
您的数据结构应该做什么。
So we have operations like insert and delete.
因此，我们有插入和删除之类的操作。
We have operations like find the min
我们有诸如查找最低
and things like successor and predecessor,
以及诸如继任者和前任者之类的东西，
or next larger, next smaller.
或下一个更大，下一个更小。
You can take any subset of these and it's an abstract data type.
您可以采用这些的任何子集，它是一种抽象的数据类型。
Insert, delete, and min is called a priority queue.
插入，删除和最小称为优先级队列。
So if you just take these first two,
因此，如果您只拿前两个，
it's called a priority queue.
它称为优先级队列。
And there are many priority queues.
并且有许多优先级队列。
This is a generic thing that you might want to do.
这是您可能想做的一般事情。
And then the data structure on the other side
然后另一边的数据结构
is how you actually do it.
是您实际的操作方式。
This is the analog of the algorithm.
这是该算法的类似物。
OK, this is the specification.
好，这是规格。
You want a priority queue.
您需要一个优先级队列。
One way to do it is a heap.
一种方法是堆。
Another way to do it is an AVL tree.
另一种方法是AVL树。
You could do it with a sorted array.
您可以使用排序数组来完成。
You could do lots of sub-optimal things, too,
您也可以做很多次优的事情，
but in particular, heaps get these two operations.
但特别是，堆会执行这两个操作。
If you want all three, you basically
如果要全部三个，基本上
need a balanced binary search tree.
需要一个平衡的二叉搜索树。
There are probably a dozen balanced binary search trees
可能有一打平衡的二叉搜索树
out there, at least a dozen balanced search trees,
那里，至少有一打平衡的搜索树，
not all binary.
并非全部二进制。
They all achieve log n.
它们都达到log n。
So it doesn't really matter.
因此，这并不重要。
There are various practical issues, constant factors,
存在各种实际问题，恒定因素，
things like that.
像这样的东西。
The main reason you prefer a heap is that it's in place.
您更喜欢堆的主要原因是它已经就位。
It doesn't use any extra space.
它不使用任何多余的空间。
Here, you've got pointers all over the place.
在这里，您到处都有指针。
You lose a constant factor in space.
您在空间上失去了不变的因素。
But from a theoretical standpoint,
但是从理论上讲
if you don't care about constant factors,
如果您不在乎恒定因素，
AVL trees are really good because they get everything
AVL树真的很好，因为它们可以得到一切
that we've seen so far and log n.
到目前为止我们已经看到并登录n。
And I'll stop there.
我会停在那里。